Inventory of the Archibald Woods Papers 1777-1893, 1783-1846
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to McKinley & Letler, n.p. 2 December 1825. (Folder 1533)
  Concerned over a director owing bank money.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Thomas Edwards, Boonsborough, Washington, County, 12 December 1825., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1534)
  Describes his tavern in Wheeling and its location.
- E[dgar] C[ampbell] Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 26 December 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1535)
  Family news from Augusta County, Virginia. Eugenius Wilson is unpopular because perceived as spearheading prosecution against two members of General Assembly, [Edward] Watts and [Francis] Billingsley for bribery. Mentions effect of death of [James] Pindall.
- John J. Allen, Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia]. 4 January 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1536)
  Suit has been instituted in Superior Court of Law [against [?] Childers?]
- Lewis Maxwell, Weston, [Lewis County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 5 January 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1537)
  Concerns about lawsuit which charges a title to land Woods is involved in is vague. Asks for patents and information.
- J. Smith, Turkey Run, [?], to [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 22 January 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1538)
  Redeems watch. Asks Woods to come survey land.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arc[hibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 January 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1539)
  Asks if a position is available at Knox & McKee for Washington Wilson. Death of Thomas Wilson.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 15 February 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1540)
  Washington [Wilson] declines position with Knox & McGee and has accepted one elsewhere. Death of [Thomas Wilson] and death of Sarah [Woods].
- W. B. Hubbard, St. Clairsville, [Ohio], to Arch[ibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 16 March 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1541)
  Suggests Woods come to next Court when Court House will be discussed.
- Geo[rge] Paull, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Arc[hibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 April 1826., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1542)
  Pork is rejected by Navy inspectors. Settled business with [Moses H.] Shepherd who will dismiss lawsuits.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Mary [(Woods)] Wilson, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 May 1826., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1543)
  Political prospects for Congress. News of Morgantown. Summarizes letter from a runaway slave.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Clarksbury, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 May 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1544)
  Progress of lawsuit in Wilson v. Woods.
- Jacob Ash, McElroy Fork, [?], to A[rchibald] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 May 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1545)
  Unable to pay money owed to Woods.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 May 1826., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1546)
  Chancellor Tucker has rendered decision. Wilson v. Woods must be decided by jury. Doddridges' arguments good. Received Booth money.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 May 1826. (Folder 1547)
  Outlines political strategy to convince Haymond not to run for Congress.
- Henry Miller, Morristown, Ohio, to Archy [Archibald] Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 June 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1548)
  Roadmakers are ready to cut drain through Woods' field.
- E. C. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 June 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1549)
  Predicts results in congressional race. Brother Norval [Wilson] married to [?] Howland.
- Benj[amin] W. Wilson, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Whe[e]ling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 June 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1550)
  Unable to pay money.
- Knox & McKee, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Creek, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia], 13 July 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1551)
  Order for flour.
- Henry Miller, Morristown, Ohio, to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 17 July 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1552)
  Builders of N[ational] Road have let water onto his garden.
- James Mitchell, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 31 July 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1553)
  Recommends [?] Kennon to purchase land.
- J[ohn] L. Sehon, Clarksb[ur]g, Virginia [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 10 August 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1554)
  Has checked lawsuits of Kershner v. England, Morris, Woods & Caldwell.
- Josias Thompson, Triadelphia [Virginia] [West Virginia], to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 September 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1555)
  Would like to be appointed superintendent of road.
- Elij[ah] McClandhan, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 September 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1556)
  Inquires about land his deceased father owned in Ohio County. If Woods never collected money for A. Hamilton, he won't from his estate which will be insolvent. McClandhan's mother died May 1824.
- David Scott, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to A[rchibald] Woods, near Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 19 September 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1557)
  William Brookover would like to rent land from Woods.
- M[ary (Woods)] Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Anne [(Poage)] Woods, n.p., 23 September 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1558)
  Darky, slave, has tried to run away twice. Is being returned to Woods family.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to John Tyler, Governor, Richmond, [Virginia], 6 October 1826., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1559)
  Concerned over money owed Northwestern Bank by a director. Recommends three names to be appointed as director.
- John Sexton, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 8 October 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1560)
  Suggests Woods direct finishing of his warehouse.
- E[dgar] C[ampbell] Wilson, Clarksburgh, [sic] [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 20 October [1826]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1561)
  Transmits money owed to Woods by [?] Maxwell.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 October 1826., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1562)
  Compromise proposed in Wilson vs. Woods. Cresap vs. Chapline's heirs was decided in favor of Cresap. Has sold Darky to man in Harrison County for $300.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 31 October [1826]., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1563)
  Thinks Doddridge will stand better chance of winning than Leffler for Congress.
- T. G. Haymond, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Archibald Woods?], 7 November 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1564)
  Concerns appointment of Woods as a director of Northwestern Bank.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arc[hibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 10 November 1826., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1565)
  Concerns Wilson v. Woods, Woods v. Booth, and Woods' place as director of Northwestern Bank of Virginia.
- Isaac Leffler, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 18 November 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1566)
  Will defend three directors of Northwestern Bank of Virginia against being surplanted.
- Richard Norris, Baltimore, [Massachusetts], to C[harles] D. Knox, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 November 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1567)
  Concerns Emily Knox's dissatisfaction with her school in Baltimore.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 November 1826., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1568)
  Does not recommend compromise in Wilson vs. Woods. Problem with directors of Northwestern Bank of Virginia T. P. Ray and Alpheus P. Wilson will attend canal convention before going to Richmond. Does not trust Thomas S. Haymond. Passes on name of George Kyger for tavern. Wilson will act as clerk in T. P. Ray's absence.
- E[dgar] C[ampbell] Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arc[hibal]d Woods, n.p. [?], 30 November 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1569)
  Maxwell expects to pay money owed to Woods.
- Daniel Steenrod, Wheeling, Creek, [Ohio County, Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arche [Archibald Woods], n.p., 5 December 1826., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1570)
  Moses Shepherd wants to meet with Woods.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 December 1826., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1571)
  Defends [Henry St. George] Tucker from charge of being an agent of Jno R. Wilson [charges perhaps levied by Philip Doddridge].
- W. D. n.p., to B[enjamin] Ruggles, Senate Chamber, [Washington, D.C.], 19 December 1626., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1572)
  Notifies Ruggles that there is already a post office named Capatina Creek in Belmont County, Ohio so suggests another name.
- Agnes Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia], to Ann [(Poage)] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], [22 December 1826?]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1573)
- A.C. Baker, Bowling Green, Missouri to sister Mrs. Ann R. Morgan, Salem, Fauquier County, Virginia, 24 December 1846., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1574)
  Travel in Missouri in winter.
- Lewis Maxwell, Weston, [Lewis County, Virginia] [West Virginia], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 26 December 1826., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1575)
  Making arrangements to pay note. Candidate for next Congress. Hopes Woods will not move against Middle Island Company.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 6 January 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1576)
  Need postal route on west side of Ohio River. Asks Woods' advice.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arc[hibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 January 1827., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1577)
  Satisfied with how situation regarding indebtedness of directors of Northwester Bank of Virginia has turned out. Yarnall, Sprigg and Shepherd together owe about $70,000. Sprigg and Shepherd re-elected. Quotes Woods' misgivings about [Henry St. George] Tucker. Should resist any change in venue in Woods vs. Wilson.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Benjamin Ruggles, Senator in Congress, Washington, City, [D.C.], 13 January 1827., 2 pages. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1578)
  Advice on a postal route west of Ohio River.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 January 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1579)
  Route has been established to serve Captina Point (now Powhattan [Powhatan Point]).
- Jer Hollister, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 January 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1580)
  Has horse for sale.
- Ja[me]s Collier, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods,[Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 31 January 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1581)
  No reply to previous letter. Will call on Woods to take deposition concerning claim of Moses Shepherd for building National Road.
- Henry Miller, Morristown, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 21 February 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1582)
  Sends dried peaches. Does not want to rent Woods' place when lease expires.
- A[nthony] D. Clarke, Captina [Belmont County, Ohio], to Archibald Woods, n.p., 5 February 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1583)
  Major Smith intends to become a tenant under Woods.
- B[enjamin] Ruggles, Washington, [D.C.], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 February 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1584)
  Post route has been established including Woodsfield.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 7 March 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1585)
  Advice in Wilson vs. Woods. Family news including the education of an orphan child.
- John Eaton, Morristown, Ohio, to Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 March 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1586)
  Damage done to Woods' land by a tenant. Suggests a [?] Davis to make 100,000 brick.
- Josiah Dillon & Son, Captina Mills, [Belmont County, Ohio] to Archable [Archibald] Woods, Powhatan, Ohio, 10 March 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1587)
  Will take along with James Smith the store and warehouse.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Richard Norris, Baltimore, [Maryland], 12 March 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1588)
  Will pay bills for daughter, Emily, and make arrangements for her trip home.
- Nicholas Rodgers, [i.e. John Eaton?], Morristown, Ohio to Archib[ald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 15 March 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1589)
  Does not consider land cleared properly by Miller.
- Michael Cresap, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 23 April 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1590)
  Wants to buy wood from Woods.
- Cornelius Okey, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 11 May 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1591)
  Has sold tanyard--asks Woods or George Paull to make out deed to William Craig, the purchaser. Business is stirring at Woodsfield.
- James Rose, Pittsburgh, [Pennsylvania], to Archibald Woods, near Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 May 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1592)
  Concerns land claimed by James McHenry. Gives information concerning McHenry's family. Probably concerns Wilson vs. Woods.
- Z. Jacobs, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 23 March 1827., 1 page. ANS. (Folder 1593)
  Asks Woods to call on him at his office.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 May 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1594)
  Concerns money owed by [?] Maxwell.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Ohio], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 30 May 1827., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1595)
  Woods v. Boothe. Has settled with Mrs. Pindall. Woods v. Wilson did not gain a change of venue and [Henry St. George Tucker's] opinion.
- A. J. McDowell, Steubenville, [Ohio], to T[homas] Woods, Cashier [Northwestern Bank of Virginia], Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 7 June 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1596)
  Asks about note for money owed by [?] Smith.
- Benj[amin] W. Wilson, n.p., to Archabald [Archibald] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 26 June 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1597)
  Inability to pay money owed to Woods.
- J. Henthorn, Sunfish, [?] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 10 July 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1598)
  Will tend to collecting money for Woods.
- Jos[eph] Woods,"Westwood" [near Nashville, Tennessee] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 12 July 1827., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1599)
  Bad health of Robert Woods. Gives news of extended family. Wants flour sent to him on a regular basis.
- Mary (Woods) Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Ann (Poage)] Woods, [Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 14 July 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1600)
- Robert F. Naylor, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 17 July 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1601)
  Sends eight dollars.
- Alexander [Ferret or Ferril?], Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 August 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1602)
  Agrees to buy land.
- Tho[mas] McClintock, Philad[elphi]a, [Pennsylvania] to Isaac P. Wilson, St. Clairsville, Ohio, 20 [October] 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1603)
  Has deposited $1520 in bank for Wilson's use. Bring deed to Philadelphia.
- Jer. Hollister, Woodsfield, [Ohio], to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 28 August 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1604)
  Shall attend a sale.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 29 August 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1605)
  Needs to stay in Morgantown to attend to client's business. Will have subpoenas served. Thinks Doddridge should be examined as a witness.
- Ja[me]s McGuire, Dillies Bottom, [Belmont County, Ohio] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia], 10 September 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1606)
  Needs aged whiskey.
- John Rector, Captain [Capteena, Belmont County, Ohio] to A[rchibald] Woods, n.p., 24 September 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1607)
  Wants to give up place. Recommends Obed Morris to have it.
- Alpheus P. Willson, n.p., to A[rchibald] Woods, Ohio County, Virginia [West Virginia], 24 September 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1608)
  Learned through Tho[ma]s S. Haymond that it is intention of Yarnal & Co. to make a violent effort to get the ascendancy in the direction of the N[orth]w[estern] Bank. Has erred in recommending Zane as a director.
- C. H. Picken, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 14 October 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1609)
  Unable to see [John] Rector.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Clarksburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia], to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 18 October 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1610)
  Encloses $250 From [?] Maxwell. Thinks Chancellor [Tucker] will refuse motion for a new trial. Jacobs and Doddridge "argued rather feebly....I explained to the Judge all the circumstances of the trial on our journey up from Morgantown to this court."
- Jos[eph] Woods,"Westwood" [near Nashville, Tennessee] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 October 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1611)
  Asks questions about the building of a turnpike since one has been authorized by legislature from Nashville to Columbia.
- Josiah Dillon, Captina Creek, Ohio, to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 23 October 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1612)
  Dispute over Woods' not putting warehouse in repair and over the price of a horse.
- H. N. Bakewell, Wellsburg, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 25 October 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1613)
  Has gotten load and a halt of clay and has filled up holes in bank which he understands is Woods' objection to taking clay.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, Virginia [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 November 1827., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1614)
  Disappointed at Chancellor Tucker's decision in Wilson v. Woods. Gives advice on next legal steps to take.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 4 November 1827., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1614A)
  Answers inquiries made by Woods in Wilson v. Woods. Doddridge upset at remark he was unwell. Has put a piece in the paper under signature of "concert" supporting Adams meeting.
- A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to W[illia]m B[ranch] Giles,[Richmond, Virginia], 8 November 1827., 1 page. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1615)
  States condition of Northwest Bank of Virginia Recommends against appointment of Moses W. Chapline or [?] Yarnall as directors.
- Notices that land in Vigo County, Indiana has been sold for taxes and redeemed, 12 November 1827., 3 items. PD. (Folder 1616)
- Memorandum of John McLure, 14 November 1827., 2 pages. MS. (Folder 1617)
  Answering questions posed by Archibald Woods about methods and cost of building National Road. Also mentions Ohio Road and McAdams Plan of road construction. Questions in handwriting of Woods.
- [Senia?] S. Salisbury, Woodsfield, [Ohio] to Archibald Woods, Wheelling, [Wheeling], Virginia [West Virginia], 19 November 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1618)
  Asks delay in paying money.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 November 1827., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1619)
  Had anti-Jackson meeting. Ladies have formed literary society which meets in Wilson's office every Monday evening in which the bible [sic] makes a part of their reading.
- Sam[ue]l Denniston, Pittsburgh, [Pennsylvania] to Cha[rle]s D. Knox, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 27 November 1827., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1620)
  Wants to rent Woods' tavern in Wheeling.
- And[re]w Woods, n.p., to Arch[ibal]d Woods, n.p., 29 November 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1621)
  Terms of land deal.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 7 December 1827., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1622)
  Must have whole record copied--not selected parts. Legal advice in Wilson vs. Woods. Believes Chancellor [Tucker] was wrong in directing issue to be tried. Advises an appeal.
- Archi[bal]d Woods, Wheeling, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Messrs. Haven & Smith, Philadelphia, [Pennsylvania], 10 December 1827., 1 page. ACyS of ALS. (Folder 1623)
  A[nthony] D. Clarke borrowed $5,000 from Woods secured by deed of trust for land. Asks it they have the funds.
- Joseph Talbott, Frederick Town, [Maryland] to A[rchibald] Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 19 December 1827., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1624)
  Will give up his house in Frederick. Then will look out for a first rate hotel. Thanks [Charles D.] Knox for writing him about Woods' hotel in Wheeling.
- M[ary (Woods)] Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to [Ann (Poage) Woods, Wheeling, Virginia] [West Virginia], 21 December 1829., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1625)
  Asks her father to visit. Discusses her children. Has clergyman boarding with them who will teach school.
- Joseph Strean, Wellsvill[e, Ohio] to [Archibald] Woods, n.p., 4 January 1828., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1626)
  Includes, ALS, of John H. Jenkins, n.p. to [Archibald] Woods, recommending [Strean?].
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 5 January 1828., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1627)
  Describes arrival of first steamboat, "Reindeer" at Morgantown. Court record of [ Wilson vs. Woods] will not be copied for a month because it is so large and clerk has other records to copy. Alpheus [P. Willson] and T. P. Ray started to Richmond to attend Anti-Jackson Convention.
- Michael Cresap, n.p., to Archibald Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 14 January 1828., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1628)
  Would like to rent a house if Woods or any of his friends buys it.
- Eug[eniu]s M. Wilson, Morgantown, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 22 January 1828., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1629)
  Has received court record of 216 pages in Wilson v. Woods. Gives legal advice for the appeal. Morgan has declared for Senate.
- Stephen Colwell, St. Clairsville, [Ohio] to Arch[ibal]d Woods, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 8 February 1828., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1630)
  Legal advice.
- Hiram Haymond, Monongalia C[oun]ty, [Virginia] [West Virginia] to Archibald Woods or [?] Chaplin, Wheeling, Virginia [West Virginia], 13 February 1828., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1631)
  Send survey of 800 acre tract at Middle Island and he will make offer.